( young boy hums " Paint It Black " )
OK .
- ( guitar strumming ) - Jackson came over to play .
( sings ) Superheroes !
I was Black Power Ranger .
He was Batman .
Jake , are you OK in there , buddy ?
I 'm OK .
Can I ask you a question ?
OK ! Time to hit the sack .
- An important question . - There we go , big guy . Come on .
( groans )
- Can I wear bugs ? - Bug pyjamas ... are all the way downstairs .
But fire trucks are here .
- Bugs . - Fire trucks .
- Bugs . - OK , bugs .
I 'll be right back .
( eerie whispering )
Does it hurt to be dead ?
- Animal . - What did I do now ?
- Can I tell him ? - If you wanna die .
- Well , your beer-addled sperm still work . - Lisa !
- You impregnated my sister again . - Bitch !
- I thought you wanted me to ? - I said " Don 't " !
The kid could have been born before he 'd notice .
- You 're not pregnant . - I feel " Congratulations " is more appropriate .
- You told her before you told me . - She 's a witch !
She took one look at me and guessed .
Say something !
Bummer .
Something else !
So ... she 's six weeks pregnant . That means the baby 's due in April , May , ...
.. June . Gemini . That 's cool . Einstein was a Gemini .
- So 's that Scottish gal from Garbage . - Will you go help Jake with his pyjamas ?
- If she 's late ... - Lisa , I swear to God , ...
.. start with the Dionne Warwick stuff , I 'll throw you out the fuckin ' window .
- So please help him with the pyjamas . - Love you , too , Tom ( ! )
Hey , this is great . I mean it .
It 's about time we had another kid . I was gonna bring it up myself .
- Really ( ? ) - Absolutely !
- This time , you gotta take some time off . - Please ! We can 't afford that !
- We can . I 'm gonna hit the overtime again . - I don 't want you to work those hours again .
You come home in a trance . You 're completely useless to me .
I 'm gonna be fine , OK ?
I 'm just gonna tell Teddy to get somebody else for the thing .
- Oh , God ! Oh , Tom ! - What ?
I 'm sorry . I completely forgot . No wonder you 're pissed off .
I 'm not pissed off . I just ... No , I 'm ... I 'm not . I 'm not .
I 'm a grown man . I shouldn 't be screwing around with some shitty band anyway .
Hey , look , l-l ... I gotta go change . You know , put on something cool .
I love you .
I 'm ... I 'm a happy guy .
You know , I 'm not gonna be a lineman forever , I promise you that .
Whaddaya mean ?
I clip ... clip wire all day . A monkey could do it .
Yeah , but they 're gonna move you into the office soon .
No , I meant , when we first got together , I said a lotta stuff about what I was gonna be , ...
.. and I just wanted you to know that , uh ... I wasn 't giving you some kinda line , ...
.. that I meant it .
I didn 't marry you because I thought you were gonna be famous .
I just liked the way your ass looked in jeans .
I never wanted to be famous . I just , uh ... I didn 't expect to be ... so ...
What ?
I don 't know .
Ordinary .
( footsteps )
( eerie whispering )
Shhh .
Hang on ! Hang on !
You know , I hope it 's a girl .
I 'm kinda sick of all these balls around the house . Except for yours , babe .
What are the odds on an educated single man being at this thing ?
And I don 't mean a GED !
- Does it matter if he 's on the boner pill ? - I wouldn 't look a gift-boner in the mouth .
( Tom ) Nice - that 's very nice , Lisa ( ! )
- Hey ! How you been ? - Hey , Tom , Tom , Tommy ! How ya doin ' ?
Oh , you would not believe the day I had .
- Take this . I 'll get another . - Thanks .
- Harry . - Tom . Taking care of the place for me ?
We 're drilling holes all over your floors ( ! ) I hope you don 't mind .
Tom , you know my squaw Sheila . Bobby , Vanessa .
- Thanks for having me . - Drink up ! Take your medicine .
Tom , how do you like the neighbourhood ?
I grew up in Bridgeport , so it 's not like it 's a foreign country .
You 're goddamn right . This is the best neighbourhood in Chicago .
We all look out for each other . That 's saying a lot as we approach the year 2000 .
- Are you running for mayor ( ? ) - Hey , did any of you guys ...
- .. see them crank dealers ... - What is Lenny doing here ?
Bobby , did you tell him you had a party ?
- Vanessa made me . We invited everybody . - To actually invite this jack-off ... !
Oh , yeah , laugh it up ( ! )
When you wake up dead with your throat cut , don 't come crying to me !
Not attracted to .
Not drunk enough for .
Frightened by !
Argh !
Don 't touch me . I 'm fine .
( Jake 's breathing )
Haven 't you heard about people being operated on when they 're under hypnosis ?
Yeah , but I don 't believe in any of that .
People who say they were hypnotised were just playing along .
- ( Tom ) Right . - Really ?
Then how could they have a scalpel stuck into their throat without even bleeding ?
- Bullshit ! - You never saw that happen !
- That 's bullshit ! - Learn another word !
Yeah , what about " narrow-minded " ?
I saw a guy in my class get a two-inch needle stuck into his arm by my instructor ...
- .. when he was under hypnosis . - Horseshit ! That better , honey ?
I saw a picture of it the next day . It left a mark .
What I don 't understand is how a person that 's been to college ...
.. can believe all that superstitious crap .
- ( Lisa ) It isn 't superstitious ! - Come on !
- I 'm practically a licensed hypnotherapist . - " Practically " ?
Isn 't that like saying " I don 't have a licence " ? Ow ! My arm !
This may come as a surprise to you , but just because you lived here for your whole life ...
.. doesn 't mean that there isn 't a whole larger world out there , ...
.. doorways you haven 't even opened , things you wouldn 't have any understanding of .
( man ) Doorways ... OK , OK . All right , Kreskin , prove it - hypnotise somebody .
- Yeah ! Do me . - No .
- Why not ? - For one , you 're hostile .
I 'm not hostile ! Do I seem hostile to anybody ?
- Uh ... yeah . - Thanks for having us . It was a great party .
Nah , nah , this is just getting good . Come on , Lisa . Hypnotise me . Come on !
- No . You 're drunk . - I 'm not drunk !
You 're not supposed to mesmerise somebody who 's been drinking !
Mesmerise ! No ! Stop !
Oh , please ! I 'm begging you . Educate the savages .
It won 't work with that kind of uncooperative attitude .
I swear to you , I 'll follow every instruction to the letter .
It still won 't work .
Come on .
What 's the worst that can happen ?
- Somebody turn out the lights . - ( man ) Oh , yeah !
- ( laughter ) - ( man ) Whoo !
( Lisa ) All right , just relax . Put your arm down . Just rest it comfortably . Just lean back .
Just be very comfortable and relaxed .
Trust me . OK ?
- Close your eyes . - Certainly , Lisa .
Now ... just listen for a moment .
Listen to the sounds of the room around you .
( woman whispers ) I don 't know why , but I 'm scared .
( Lisa ) Now I want you to pretend you 're in a theatre .
A movie theatre ,
You 're the only one there .
It 's one of those great old movie palaces .
When you look around , it 's a huge , empty theatre .
You notice that the walls of the theatre are painted in black .
The seats ... are covered in black .
And in the whole pitch-black theatre , ...
.. there 's only one thing you can see , and that 's the white screen .
You 'll notice there are letters on the screen - tall , thick , black letters .
But they 're out of focus , so you drift closer to them in your chair , trying to read them .
You 're very comfortable now . It 's your favourite chair .
You 're drifting closer and closer , staring at the letters .
Very relaxed now . Your legs are relaxed .
Your arms are limp and heavy .
You 're almost close enough to read the letters now .
They start to come into focus .
The letters spell " sleep " .
Sleep .
No !
- What the hell was that ? - ( laughter )
- What ? What ? What ? - Are you OK ? You had to be faking it .
That was the weirdest goddamn thing I 've seen in my life !
Congratulations , Tom ! You 're one of the lucky eight percent !
- You still have tears on your cheeks . - What the hell did she do to me ?
- Christ , I 'm thirsty . - Whaddaya mean ? What eight percent ?
There 's only eight percent of the population that 's , like , highly hypnotisable .
Almost anybody can go under a little , ...
.. but not way under - not freaky under , like he did .
- How 's your hand ? - Whaddaya mean ?
I stuck a safety pin in your hand and asked you to bleed on one side , but not the other .
- Which I can 't believe you did ! - You were very cooperative .
It was a side of you I hadn 't seen before .
- That happened ? - You said it didn 't hurt .
( man # 1 ) To hell with the pin ! I wanna know more about your Joey Luca .
- ( laughter ) - ( man # 2 ) Yeah , right !
- Who ? - ( man # 1 ) Joey Luca is the kid who ...
.. used to pound the shit out of you when you were 12 .
You told us all about it . You were crying . It was hysterical !
- Shut up . - It was very moving , Tom .
Joey Luca ! Jesus Christ , I haven 't thought about him ...
( sniffles )
Hey .
Can we go home ? I ... I feel kinda strange .
Yeah . Yeah , sure .
( exasperated sigh )
Close your eyes .
( kissing noises )
( she pants )
Uh !
What 's the matter ?
Don 't stop .
- Don 't stop . - OK .
( moans )
Ugh ! Jesus Christ ! Oh , my God !
- What ? - I-l ... I 'm seeing things .
What do you mean ?
Oh , no , no , no . Wait , wait , wait . I-l can 't right now .
- Then you were faking it extremely well . - Ohh ...
Wait . Stop , stop , stop ! It 's too weird .
Baby , that wasn 't weird . I could show you weird .
( sighs )
I felt like I was being attacked .
Thanks ( ! )
I 'm sorry , I didn 't ... I didn 't ... ( nervous gasps )
I-l ... I 'll be right back .
What the fuck ... ? !
Ah ... Agh ... Agh !
Arghhh ...
Argh !
- ( eerie voices ) - Agh ! Agh !
( distorted speech )
- Hey , Jake . - You 're awake now , Daddy .
Are you OK ?
Yeah . Yeah , I guess .
I just don 't feel so good right now .
Don 't be afraid of it , Daddy .
- What was it , then ? An hallucination ? - Yeah , a bunch of ' em .
It 's like all these thoughts just kept coming . You believe this ? I got seven calls .
Well , if it never happened before , it had to be the hypnosis .
I had this headache and I was thirsty as hell .
Jake ! I know you 're not watching that monster tape again ( ! )
- ( TV off ) - Who was the woman ?
I don 't know . Maybe somebody I was just remembering . She didn 't look familiar .
- Did you fuck her ? - You gotta be kidding .
No . I mean , was she someone you used to go out with ?
You 're jealous of my hallucination ? Hmm , you are pregnant !
- You should call Lisa . - No , she 's the one that fucked up my brain .
- Then she has to unfuck it . - Ooh ! Agh ! Fuck ! Fuck !
Don 't swear so much !
Hang on , hang on ! Let me get my bearings here .
I have ... I have absolutely no caffeine in my system , you know .
OK . You 're asking me if I gave you a post ...
.. posthypnotic suggestion .
Did you leave anything else behind when you were inside my brain ?
- Nothing ! - Tell the truth , Lisa .
Tom ! Please , this is insulting . You know , I have done this before .
OK , good . I-l was ... I was just making sure .
It was just a harmless one anyway .
- What ? - Did it actually work ?
- What did you say ? - I don 't wanna tell you . You 're grouchy .
Lisa , I swear to God ... !
Well , you know I 've always said I think you need to be a little more open-minded ?
- Yeah ... - So I just said that .
" After you wake up , your mind will be completely open , like an open door , ...
.. open to receive everything around you . "
- What 's that supposed to do ? - Fuck if I know ! I never said it before .
- Why ? Did something happen ? - Jesus Christ !
Relax . OK ? I opened a door , that 's all . You know , therapists do it all the time .
It releases repressed memories , whatever you got back there .
- For you , it was probably old Mannixreruns . - I gotta get back to work .
OK . Alrighty , then ( ! )
( rings )
No ! No more calls for Lisa !
- ( bleeps ) - Hey , Lise , it 's me .
Call me when you wake up . Is there any way you could baby-sit for us on Friday ?
I did ! I told him !
( eerie whispering )
What 's your name ?
OK .
.. but then I gotta hear about it for a month .
I called everyone who could possibly do it and no one 's free .
- Call Vanessa . - Huh ?
I said , call Vanessa and ask her about Debbie .
Anyway , call me back . Bye .
Debbie ? That 's the girl who baby-sits for them ?
Yep .
Oh , great idea . Pray she 's free .
- How 'd you know about Debbie ? - Samantha told me .
Hey , Vanessa . Are you guys going out Friday night ?
( doorbell )
Hi . I 'm Debbie .
Kozak ... ?
Tom Witzky .
- Hi , Debbie . I 'm Maggie . - Hi .
Thanks for coming . Jake 's asleep already and he hardly ever wakes up .
A band could play in his room and he wouldn 't hear it !
His room 's upstairs , kitchen 's back there . Just help yourself if you want anything .
Here , have a seat . This is the baby monitor .
It 's on B in his room , so you should hear everything .
- You wanna watch a movie ? - I got a book .
It shouldn 't be later than midnight , if that 's OK .
- Perfect . - Great . I 'll just grab my coat .
Hel-lo !
- ( sighs ) - Ready ?
- Yeah . Just about . - OK .
Hey . Uh ... where 'd you find that girl Debbie ?
Vanessa gave me her number . Everybody uses her . It 's cool .
- Another headache ? - Too much caffeine .
Oh . OK , let 's go .
Bye .
I think that Damon kid is doing a great job and everything , ...
.. and yeah , the kid 's got a decent arm , but high-school football is about ...
.. power , it 's about running the goddamn football - it always has been .
What did you play in high school ?
- Piano , mostly . - Oh , Jesus ! Sorry . Here , you want some ?
Anyway , Adam ... and I admit that I am biased , ...
.. but my kid is having a helluva season and it 's like nobody even notices .
If they gave him the ball , he could break a thousand yards !
And that 's in an eight-game season . Jesus Christ !
Why don 't you just lick ' em when they walk by ?
Frank says the average guy carries around a hard-on two hours out of every day .
- Three for him . - See , now I got a picture of that !
One of these days , she 's gonna find one of my .38s and pop a cap in my ass !
He 'll stick it in a bowl of soup if it 's still warm .
( Jake 's breathing )
Go ! Go !
- Are you OK ? - Yeah . Yeah , I 'm fine .
( Jake 's breathing )
Over a thousand yards , we 're talking college scholarship !
Hey , come on ... The kid can write his own ticket .
And that 's good for everybody . It 's good for the whole goddamn neighbourhood .
He 's gonna go a helluva lot further than lever did .
Look at the quality of tail he gets . He passed me in that department when he was 14 .
Come on ! While we 're young , huh ?
( Jake 's breathing )
( short breath )
( silence )
You scared me !
( whispers ) She 's downstairs , I think .
( whispers ) I don 't know . I haven 't seen her yet .
( giggles )
Jake ?
( whistle blows )
- What 's the matter ? - Something 's wrong .
What ?
( Jake ) I have a secret to tell you .
Promise , promise , promise ?
Samantha says it 's always dark where she is .
Who did you say ?
Samantha .
You ... you talked to Samantha ?
Yeah !
When ?
All the time .
- Where ? - Here . In my house .
That 's not true .
Go .
Go !
- It isn 't true . - I don 't tell lies !
Samantha was here ? Here , in your house ?
- You 're hurting my arm ! - Was she here ? !
- Let go of me ! - Come on , you 're coming with me . Let 's go .
She 's taking him away .
Put me down ! Put ... me ... down !
( horn blares )
Tom !
Jake !
( Tom ) Jake !
- What the hell ... ? - She took him .
- What ? ! - The fucking baby-sitter .
Oh , my God !
He 's ... He 's not in there .
- Where are you going ? - I don 't know !
He 's in there .
- Jake ! - Daddy !
- That 's him ! - Wait ! Where do you think you 're going ? !
Take it easy ! Stop ! Stop ! Take it easy . Take it easy .
- Gimme my kid . - Tell me where she is ! No !
You tell me where she is ! You tell me where she is !
- Keep your hands off her ! - Hey ! Hey , hey ! Everybody shut up !
- Are you OK ? - That girl kidnapped our son .
- Is that your child ? - Ask about Samantha .
I 'm asking about the boy , who doesn 't look like he 's yours !
- I can explain this . - I 'm not talking to you . I 'm talking to her .
- Is that boy your child ? - No .
She was baby-sitting for us . We never ...
What you 've done is a felony . You can go to jail for this !
- Where were you taking him ? - I wasn 't taking him anywhere !
- Then why did ya bring him here ? - I wanna press charges .
She came here because of me . I 'm her mother .
- Her mother ? - When are you gonna ask about Samantha ?
- Who ? - My oldest daughter . She ran away .
No , she was kidnapped , and the little boy said he saw her !
We haven 't heard from her in a long time . We filed a police report .
- Nobody returns our phone calls . - Jake said he talked to her .
He said Samantha is in their house . Is that her ? !
- Stay away from him . - Look at the picture .
- Let go of me ! - Look at the picture .
- ( Maggie ) This is ridiculous . - Will you look at the picture , please ?
- I have never seen her before in my life . - What about you ?
No . I 'm sorry . I 've never seen her .
- No ... No . No , they 're lying ! - You wanna file charges ?
- Yes ! - No .
- What ? - Come on , let 's just , uh ... forget about it .
Let 's go home .
Are you nuts ? What about the next people she baby-sits for ?
It was her . Samantha .
That girl in the picture , she 's the same girl I saw on our couch .
See , why ... Why did you ask that girl Debbie to baby-sit for us ? Why her ?
I couldn 't find anybody else . I was on the phone and Jake said ...
( Jake hums " Paint It Black " )
Jake ? Do you remember the other day when we were talking in the kitchen ?
I was looking for a baby-sitter , remember ? You said Samantha told you about Debbie .
Do you remember that ?
Mommy 's asking you a question , bud .
Is Samantha someone who talks to you sometimes , Jake ?
- Can you remember ... - Don 't ask the boy any more questions .
( adult voice ) Talk to me .
- What did you say ? - ( Jake 's voice ) Huh ?
Jake . W-what did you say just now ?
- Nothing . - Let me hear that voice again .
- Come on . Say it again . Use that voice again . - Tom !
Come ... Come on , Jake . Come on . Use the voice again .
- Tom ! - Make the voice again , Jake . You can do it .
- Tom , don 't ! - How do you ...
- Tom , please ! - It 's all right ! It 's all right !
- OK ! - What are you doing ? Hey ! Hey !
I 'm talking to him !
- Hey , what 's the matter with you ? - What do you think ?
Well , I ... I 'm just trying to have a conversation with my kid .
A perfectly normal conversation for a five-year-old ( ! )
- Don 't be afraid of it . - Why the hell not ?
I don 't know . That 's what he told me .
This is where it happened . This is where I saw her .
- You 're different . You feel different . - I leaned back and there she was . She 's 18 .
- Longish hair . Is that what you saw ? - I wish you ...
- Maggie , please ! - God !
Or ... or maybe you don 't see her , huh ? You just hear her ? Is that what it is ?
- Tom , stop it ! - I need to find a way to make her come back .
- Maybe if I hang out here long enough , ... - I 'm talking to you !
.. maybe she 'll come back . Maybe you could talk to her . Help me out here .
- Hey , come on ! Hey ! What 's the problem ? - Knock it off !
I don 't wanna talk about this because it scares Mommy .
( ~ rock music )
- Turn it up , man . - What ?
Turn it up . Up !
( music gets louder )
Tom is looking especially together today .
He grunted a very pleasant greeting at me , actually .
He 's becoming sort of monosyllabic . Nothing wrong with that guy .
Nothing a little lithium couldn 't cure !
- I 'm a jerk . I 'm sorry . - No ...
Are you OK ?
Over there ! In the door !
( Harry ) If you live on the base , your room and board 's covered .
- ( Bobby ) You still gotta get up early . - I 'll retire , make a coupla down payments .
When I take off the uniform , I 'm a landlord already .
Five years later , I got three houses .
- Hey . Hey , Har . - How 're ya doin ' ?
Whaddaya know about that girl Samantha Kozak ?
Samantha Kozak . Why do I know that name ?
Brownish hair , 16 or 17 years old . Used to live around here .
- Oh , yeah , yeah . I remember her , I think . - Let 's go .
Hey , Kurt ! Come here for a second .
Like he ever tells me anything , right ?
Get over here !
Say , you know that Kozak girl ?
- Uh ... Debbie . - No , no , no , the other one . Samantha .
Oh , you mean the retard . Yeah , she ran away .
Yeah , that 's right . I remember that . So , what about her ?
Oh , I ... I just been thinking about her a lot .
Why ?
Her sister baby-sat for us .
Oh .
This is the first time he 's been out in a week .
He hasn 't gone to work . He sleeps 12 hours a night .
He 's used up all his sick days . If he doesn 't show up on Monday , they 'll dock him . I ...
I can 't get him more than six feet from the couch .
- Why ? - That 's where she appeared to him .
Ah .
I 'm not shocked that there 's another woman .
Of course , the fact that she 's dead gives one pause .
We are talking about a ghost here , aren 't we , Maggie ?
She took off , uh ... last March . With a black guy , I think .
Hey , Harry . Did she ever live in our house ?
No , no , no . I just ... I just bought that one . You 're the first tenants .
Tom and Jake , it 's like they have this private club or something .
They sit in the living room and whisper , and , as soon as I walk in , they both shut up .
You know what you need to do ? Find a young priest with smouldering good looks ...
.. who can guide you through this .
I 'm kidding , but I 'm not .
Look , I give Tom a lotta shit , but the truth is , you guys are the best couple on earth .
This is on you now , Maggie . Get some help . Find out why this is happening .
There is a reason .
You won 't be the first woman who 's had to hold an insane family together .
Tom 's not crazy .
Oh , yes he is . But at least he 's getting interesting .
Sports flash ! Sports flash !
211 yards rushing on Friday night .
That 's a total of 894 yards , with two games to go .
The kid needs 106 yards . That 's 53 a game .
He could walk through the next two games and still break a thousand !
- Frank , what about you ? Do you know her ? - Who ?
Tom was asking about that Kozak girl from over by Baldwin .
- You remember : the one who ran away ? - The retard .
Shut up , Lenny . Don 't use that word .
- He 's just kinda slow . - What ? Retard ? !
Goddammit , Lenny , shut your fuckin ' pie hole !
- Hey , hey , hey ! - Heads up !
- What are you doing ? ! - Hey , hey , hey !
Somebody 's always gotta ruin it . They can 't ever just be nice .
Frank . What are you doing here ?
They 're gonna kill you , Tommy .
You and Maggie both .
Why would you say something like that , Frank ?
This is a decent neighbourhood .
Hey , are you OK ?
Where 's Sheila ? Is she at home ?
Listen , I 'm gonna go see if Sheila 's at home .
OK ?
- ( car horn ) - In the house ! Come on , both of you !
( dog snarls )
( police siren )
( Adam ) Come in !
Hi . Is your mom at home cos your dad 's ...
Hey ... you wanna see what I 've got ?
Sure .
That 's great . Is that one of your dad 's ?
Not today . Come here .
Oh , why don 't you just put the gun away , Adam ?
- Come on , man . Come here . - Those things make me kinda nervous .
- Then this will make you really nervous . - Whoa , whoa , whoa ! Don 't do that !
Don 't !
Argh !
Please don 't be under there .
Oh , boy .
Frank ?
- ( car horn ) - In the house ! Come on , both of you !
( dog snarls )
( police siren )
( barking )
( gunshot )
Adam !
Adam ! Open the door !
Oh , my God . Oh , God !
Help !
Am I awake ... or asleep ?
( Sheila ) Oh , my God ! Oh , my God , my baby !
- Hold on . Hold on . - Let me ... Let me go !
- Oh , my God ! Oh , my God ! - ( Frank ) Is he alive ? Is he alive ?
Oh , my God , Adam ! Oh , my God ! Oh , my God !
Adam ! Adam !
I 'm gonna take him for a walk or something .
- Come on , sweetie pie . Let 's get your jacket . - Where are we going ?
( Maggie ) Ha-ha !
- Well ! Hello , there ! - Well , hello ... there .
( ~ bagpipes )
Listen ! Music !
It 's beautiful !
Hey ! Jake , wait up !
( ~ " New World Symphony " by Dvorak )
I don 't think we 're supposed to be here , sweetie . Come on , let 's go . This way .
Whoa ! This place is cool !
Come on , honey . Let 's go get some lunch .
Mom ! What 's this thing ?
- I don 't know . Let me take a look . - It looks like some kinda stone .
- Either that , or it 's a medal . - Yeah , I think it is .
- " Served in the ... " - Look . A flag .
- Everything OK ? - It 's fine . Just fine .
- We 're not supposed to be here ? - Hm ?
- Oh , no . It 's fine . Really . - Oh .
OK . See you later .
The boy 's got the eyes on him , doesn 't he ?
X-ray .
Not you , though .
Possibly Daddy ?
They 're not the only ones .
Tell Daddy to come by and see me a little later tonight .
He might learn a few things .
Bye , Jake .
Bye , Neil .
His name is Neil .
( plucks string )
Try that , Daddy .
Why do I know that song ?
I 'll be home right after the movie .
I know it . I know it !
I said , I won 't be late .
OK .
Bye , Mom . Bye , Maggie .
Oh , hello .
I don 't know if I 'm in the right place . I 'm looking for Neil .
- ( speaks Korean ) - Excuse me ? I ...
- ( speaks Korean ) - I 'm sorry ...
( speaks Korean )
Shit !
( softly ) Shit ! Shit ! Shit ! Shit !
( knocks on door )
I wanna see Neil .
Wait here .
I don 't know her .
What are you doing ? I said the boy 's father . I said tell him to come .
He 'd never do it . He 'd kill me if he knew I was talking to you about this . He 's so paranoid .
What 's the story , man ? Close the fucking door !
- So are they . I can 't let you in . - Who are they ?
Look , man , this ain 't no freak show in here ! Close the damn door !
Look , you just gotta get outta here .
My husband is losing his mind .
I don 't know why , but I think you do .
You can tell me what you know , but you can 't tell me to go away because I 'm not moving .
- How long has he had it ? - Just a few days .
- What happened ? A car wreck ? - No .
- A child die ? - No !
- Did he kill someone ? - He was hypnotised .
- Is that what started it ? - It comes and it goes .
Some people have it for five seconds . Some , their whole lives .
He 's a receiver now . Everything 's coming in .
He can 't stop it . He can 't slow it down . He can 't even figure it out .
It 's like he 's in a tunnel with a flashlight , but the light only comes on once in a while .
He gets a glimpse of something , but not enough to know what it is .
Just enough to know it 's there .
- Jake , too . - Your son ?
Much better flashlight .
- Does he know what it wants yet ? - What who wants ?
He saw a ghost , didn 't he ? What did it ask him to do ?
- She didn 't ask anything . - Maybe he wasn 't listening .
She 's asked for something , and now she 's waiting , ...
.. getting more and more pissed off that he 's not doing it .
If he doesn 't do her thing , she 'll never go away .
( voice on TV )
Agh !
Kill her ! Kill her ! Kill her !
- ( screaming on TV ) - Hey !
- Absolutely not ! - Oh , please , please , please !
- Five more minutes . Five more minutes . - No , zero minutes . Oh , this is cool .
- " The Mummy " gives you nightmares . - No fair !
I know . I 'm gonna take a bath . Are you OK for ten minutes ?
Whatever !
How do I know this song ?
I know I know this song . I know it . I know it .
Agh ! Freezing !
Round up your weapons , folks !
- Charge ! - ( ~ jolly music )
I don 't wanna talk right now .
Hey !
~ Rabbit , rabbit , rabbit , rabbit , rabbit
~ Rabbit , rabbit , rabbit
( hums )
No , no ...
Tom ? I think the pilot blew out on the water heater again .
Can you go light it for me ?
Hello ? !
Or I could go light it .
( TV )
Thanks , Colonel .
( bloodcurdling scream )
I said no !
( humming )
Ah , bummer !
( winces in pain )
Agh !
- Hey ! That is the most amazing ... - ( TV distortion )
( moaning )
Oh !
Agh !
Ow !
Arghh !
Tom ?
Tom ! Breathe !
Ohhh !
- Ugh ! - What happened ?
- She 's there . - What ?
She 's there .
( eerie moaning )
What ?
( Maggie ) Oh , my God !
( hammering on door )
I ... I want you to hypnotise me again . All this shit - I want it out , I want it gone .
- I want it all to stop . Right now ! - Come right in . I want you to meet Clarita .
Oh . Hi . Sorry .
Sorry , I ...
Look , do you think that you could ... ?
- Could she ... ? - Yeah ...
Clarita , perdóname . Mi cuñado está un poco loco . ¿ Nos dejas solas , por favor ?
- ¿ Ahora ? - Sí . Sí .
¡ Fantástico ! En medio de la noche me tengo que parar en medio de la calle ...
- .. en este barrio de mierda a buscar un taxi . - I know . I ...
- Well , gracias . - De nada .
( door slams )
OK , you gotta , uh ... slow down . OK ?
You gotta be a little patient with me here cos I got a confession to make .
Y 'see , we ... we just smoked this great big fatty a few minutes before you walked in , ...
- .. so this is blowing my mind a bit extra . - Listen to me . Listen to me !
- Yeah ? - Whatever ... door you opened in my brain , ...
.. l want you to shut it .
- Now ! - OK .
I 'll do it . OK . I can do that .
Close your eyes .
OK . Just like last time , I want you to just focus and concentrate .
Listen to the sounds of the room , listen to the sounds of your breathing .
Look at the back of your eyelids . Do you see anything there ?
- Could you just get to it , please ? - All right . All right .
I want you to pretend you 're back in the movie theatre .
It 's very dark , ...
.. and in the whole pitch-black theatre , the only thing you can see is the white screen .
As you focus on the screen , you begin to drift closer to it in your chair .
You 'll notice that there are letters on the screen - tall , thick , black letters .
But they 're out of focus , so you begin to drift closer to them .
- ( gasps ) Someone 's here . - No , it 's empty .
( Tom ) But there 's someone else in here .
- No , you 're alone in the theatre , Tom . - No . No , I 'm not .
- ( Lisa ) Your feet and your ankles are relaxed . - ( Tom ) No . Hard to breathe .
( Lisa ) Your hands are limp and heavy . Your ... your arms ...
- ( Tom ) No air ! No air ! - Tom , I want you to look at the screen .
Look at the screen .
Hey .
You can read the letters now . You 're right up next to them .
Tom ! Look at the screen !
No !
Wow ! What ... what happened ? Are you OK ?
You need to sit down . What was happening there was very next level .
You should have seen your face . D 'you want a beer ?
Are you feeling better ? What happened ?
I 'm supposed to dig .
Hi !
Hello ? !
Anybody home ?
Wow ! Look what I 'm not cleaning up .
Interesting !
( digging )
( sighs ) OK !
( Tom grunts )
Hi , honey . What you doin ' ?
Dad said I 'm supposed to dig .
Oh .
Nice ( ! )
Tom .
- Tom ! - Oh !
- You scared me . - I scared you ?
- What are you doing ? - I 'm supposed to dig .
- Whaddaya mean ? - I 'm supposed to dig .
Who says ?
( panting )
I see . And what 's Jake doing ?
Jake ... is helping .
- Why are you doing this ? - The water softens up the dirt .
No . I mean ...
Could you just stop for a second ?
- Tom ! Can you turn around and look at me ? - What ... exactly don 't you understand ?
I 'm supposed to dig .
- Why are you digging ? - I 'm searching .
- What are you searching for ? - The question is not what .
We both know very well what , even though we don 't wanna admit it .
The question , Maggie , which you can plainly see I am very busy trying to answer ...
The question is where .
Don 't worry , he 's OK .
- ( whispers ) It 's not over there . - We 're calling the police .
And tell them what , exactly ? Huh ?
Practise it ! Run it by me once . I wanna see how it sounds out loud .
Anything else ?
Tom , why don 't you come inside with me ?
I wanna talk to you . You 're not yourself right now .
This is just fucking typical !
Now , what do you want me to do , Maggie , huh ?
You want me to go inside and just , uh ... sit down on the couch in front of the TV ...
.. and drink beer until I fall asleep , and maybe repeat the whole thing again tomorrow ?
- Be quiet ! - And the day after and the day after ?
- ( Maggie ) Oh , just stop ! - Until ... until ...
Until I ... I grab my chest and die ?
I mean , this ... this is the most important thing that 's ever happened to me .
I mean , this is ... this is the most ... important thing ...
.. that I have ever done in my whole life , in my whole stupid life !
And you want me to just stop ? !
No ! No , I won 't stop !
I won 't stop ! I won 't stop !
Eight years , I 've known you .
Not once have you talked to me like this . Not once .
And if you do it again , I swear to God ...
And you know what ? When you talk about how ordinary you are and your stupid life , ...
.. you 're saying " Our stupid life , " which I don 't think is particularly stupid .
So how the fuck am I supposed to feel about that ?
Are you gonna drink that ?
I 'm sorry .
OK , I 'm not sorry .
- Who 's that from ? - My brother Steve .
- My grandma 's going back in the hospital . - No , she ...
What ?
Nothing .
( phone rings )
What is it ?
Hello ?
Oh , Steve . I 'm sorry , we 've been so busy . I was just about ...
What ?
She did ?
How am I doing , Dad ?
You 're doing great , kid . You 're doing great .
I 'm so sorry , baby .
You knew .
You knew , didn 't you ?
When is the funeral ?
Sunday . We should leave as soon as we can .
Oh .
You ... you want me to go with you ?
I just thought , with your family and everything ...
Do I want you to go with me ... to my grandmother 's funeral ?
She practically raised me ! Of course I want you to come .
It 's just , I 'm kinda in the middle of something here .
( glass cracks )
( frustrated grunts )
$ 800 a month ! Can 't get any fucking water !
Fuck !
( pipes groan )
( banging )
( grunting )
( frustrated yell )
Tools .
( groans )
Damn !
Piece of shit !
( machine hums )
Haa-ha-ha-ha !
Yaaaaa !
( yelling and drilling )
It 's a rented house !
( thunder )
( phone rings )
- ( Tom ) Hello ? - ( Maggie ) It 's me .
- Oh , hey . Hey , baby , how 're ya doin ' ? - I 'm OK .
- How 's your family ? - Drunk , fighting with each other .
Listen , Maggie , I 'm so sorry . I mean , I ... I should be there with ya . I 'm an asshole .
Yeah , well , you have your good points .
- How do you feel ? - Oh , fine . Fine . You know ...
Much ... much ... much better . Everything 's fine here . Really good .
No , uh ...
- No more digging ? - No . Uh-uh . Back to normal .
I 'm sorry , too . I wish I hadn 't stormed out . I shouldn 't have left you alone .
I deserved it .
Why don 't you come up here with us ? You could make it in an hour .
- Oh , no , I can 't really do that . - Why not ?
I 'm not supposed to use the truck for personal trips .
- I 'll pick you up . I 'll leave right away . - Oh , no , no , baby . Don 't do that . That 's crazy .
- ( growls ) - I gotta go .
- I 'll just pull up front and honk . Bye . - No , no , no ! No !
( sighs )
( thunder )
( aggressive grunting )
OK , bub , you ready to go ?
I 'm scared to go home . I wanna stay at Uncle Steve 's house .
- Why are you scared ? - Because of the feathers .
What feathers ?
I don 't know . I just saw feathers .
It 's OK . I 'll watch him .
OK . You be good .
Mom ! Wait !
You forgot this .
( heavy rain )
( thunderclap )
( Adam ) Hi !
Hi .
Come here a sec .
- What ? - Come closer . I can 't hear you .
- Are you talking to me ? - I wanna show you something .
You wanna show me something ?
Well , yeah . I don 't see anybody else around .
- What is it ? - It 's a surprise .
It 's really great . Come on ! You won 't believe it .
Come on ! It 's freezing !
Hey ! Happy St Patrick 's Day !
- What 's the surprise ? - ( chuckles ) Don 't you have it ?
- Oh , yeah . The surprise , huh ? - The surprise .
- You need another drink . - No , I got the spins .
Drink , motherfucker , drink !
- I don 't think there is a surprise . - Oh , yeah , there is . Yeah , there is .
The surprise is we decided we wanna be your friends .
- You do ? - ( Kurt ) Yeah .
- Why do you wanna be my friends now ? - Are you kidding ? Look at yourself .
Uh-uh , look .
You can take your coat off , you know .
- You want a drink ? - I 'm not supposed to .
Don 't you do anything you 're not supposed to ? Huh ?
I do .
Yeah .
Momma , you are hot !
Come on , let 's be friends , huh ?
Well , ...
.. you can kiss me if you want to .
Yeah ... Yeah .
- Not ... not like that , OK ? - OK . OK . OK ...
Agh ! Ouch !
- I wanna go home . - Not now , no , no . Come on ...
- I 'll be your friend . - I want to , but ...
Just be nice to me , huh ? Be a good girl . You are a good girl , aren 't you ?
- I have to go home . - How about a helmet wash ?
I have to go home . I have to go home !
( screams )
( retches )
( hysterical screaming )
No ! Stop !
Shut up ! Shut up !
Shut ... Argh ! God !
Shut up ! Argh !
Make her stop , man ! Make her stop screaming !
Shut her up , man !
( ~ " Paint It Black " by Gob )
Use your jacket or something ! Put it over her face !
Shut up !
( muffled screaming )
( gasps for breath )
~ I could not foresee this thing happening to me
( Jake hums the tune )
Oh , my God !
What the fuck did you do that for ?
- Is she dead ? - No shit , she 's dead !
Oh , my God !
- Look at her tongue , man . - I am not here .
I 've never seen nobody dead before .
- I can 't be here . - It 's fucking gross .
This isn 't happening .
Fucking plastic over her face ! Good thinking , Adam ( ! )
Well , what do we do now ?
How 's he doin ' ?
He might make it . He might not .
Sheila 's over at the hospital . I 'm gonna head over .
Frank ... I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry because ... I think I know why Adam shot himself .
And ... I gotta call the police about it .
And I don 't want you to hear it from them .
And I don 't want Sheila to read about it in the paper .
I-l ... I think you have a right to know before anybody else .
What are you talking about , Tom ?
Come with me .
Wait here for a second .
It better be important .
Come on ! Come on , come on , come on , come on !
( Frank ) How the hell did you find this ?
Does it matter ?
Well , you don 't know if it was Kurt and Adam .
Yeah , I do .
But you don 't have anything to ...
Tom , you 're talking like a goddamn lunatic ! That 's what people are gonna say .
I-it 's just a body . It doesn 't prove anything .
She 's ...
She 's got somebody 's hair in her hand .
They 're gonna be able to tell whose it is .
Hey , Frank .
We ... we gotta call the cops .
What were we supposed to do ?
It was an accident .
The kids come to us , she 's already dead .
The damage is done . There 's nothing anybody can do to bring her back .
But these kids got ... everything ahead of them .
So what were we supposed to do , Tom ?
Send our sons to jail for the rest of their lives because of her ?
Who are you planning to shoot with that ?
- Get the hell outta here , Tom . - Hey , Frank ... come on upstairs .
We ... we could talk about this .
I 've been living with this for ... six months .
Six fucking months !
Do you think anything you have to say is gonna make one bit of difference to me ? !
- Get the hell outta here ! - I-I 'm not leaving until ...
Get out !
( gunshot )
( hammering on door )
- Hi . - Hi . ( clears throat ) Hi .
- Well , it 's really pouring , huh ? - Yeah , looks like it .
You got a minute ?
No , I 'm ... I 'm ... kinda busy right now .
It 's important .
I-l don 't really have time to talk right now , Harry .
Ah , Jesus ! This rain , huh ? !
( Tom ) Harry , like I said , you know , I 'm really kind of busy right now .
Kurt , I know you weren 't raised in a barn . Close that door .
Maybe I could call you later or something ?
Tom , we got ourselves a serious problem here .
Whaddaya mean ?
What the hell you think you 're doing to my house ?
I heard all this pounding going on . I thought I 'd check it out .
I didn 't think you 'd be wrecking the place !
What 's the matter with you ?
Oh , don 't worry . I 'm gonna ... I 'm gonna take care of that .
I-l was trying to fix your water main , you know - it was leaking , ...
.. and I couldn 't get to it from underneath the house .
I-I mean ... I-l couldn 't get under the house to get to it .
Is that right ?
Damn . A lotta water damage ?
Some .
Can I look around ?
Yeah . Yeah , sure . Sure . Help yourself .
Maybe you 'd better show me where it 's at .
Well , you guys 'll be able to see . I-l gotta take off right now .
I 'm almost afraid to look .
- Drink it . - Right .
Hurry up .
The water main doesn 't run under the house .
Well , I know that now .
Shit , Tom .
Argh !
( Harry ) Get him on the rug .
- Don 't look at him . Roll him over . - Yeah .
( Harry ) Let 's go ! All right , ...
.. get outta the way .
( repeated beeps of car horn )
( glass smashing )
Tom ?
( flicks light switch )
Are you here ?
Shit !
Argh !
- ( Harry ) Out of the way , Kurt ! - ( gunshot )
Arghh !
They were gonna kill you , Tommy . You and Maggie both .
- ( softly ) Are you OK ? - ( softly ) Yeah .
( Maggie sobs )
Cold-blooded murder .
I can 't let something like that happen .
Not here .
This was a decent neighbourhood .
( ~ " It 's Not The Spotlight " by Beth Orton )
~ If I ever feel the light again
~ Shining down on me
~ I don 't have to tell you
~ How welcome it would be
~ I felt the light before
~ But I let it slip away
~ And I just keep on believing that it 'll come back some day
~ It 's not the spotlight
~ It 's not the candlelight
~ It 's not the streetlights
~ Just some old street of dreams
~ It ain 't the moonlight
~ Not even the sunlight
~ But I 've seen it shining in your eyes and you know what I mean
( eerie whispering )
( female voice ) Jake ...
Jake ...
( voices grow louder )
~ La-da-da , da-da-da
( ~ " Hello " by Poe )
~ Hello , hello
~ Hello , hello , hello
~ Are you out there ?
~ Oh
~ Oh-oh
~ La-da-da , da-da-da
~ Oh
~ MOD , are you out there ?
~ I can 't see your face but you left a trace
~ On a data back-road that I almost erased
~ Not even God takes this long to get back
~ So get back
~ Cos I hit a fork in the road , I lost my way home
~ Cut off from the main line like a disconnected modem
~ Hello ?
~ Tap in the code , I 'll reach you below
~ No one should brave that underworld alone
~ Hello , hello , hello
~ How do I reach you ?
~ Oh
~ Oh-oh
~ La-da-da , da-da-da
~ Oh
~ Word has it on the wire
~ That you don 't know who you are
~ Well , if you could jack into my brain , you 'd know exactly what you mean here
~ Mothers are trails on stars in the night
~ Fathers are black holes that suck up the light
~ That 's the memory I filed on the fringe
~ Along with the memory of the pain you lived in
~ Hello
~ I don 't have the password , but the path is chain-linked
~ So if you got the time , set the tone to sync
~ Tap in the code
~ Hello , hello
~ Are you out there ?
~ Oh
~ Oh-oh
~ La-da-da , da-da-da
~ Oh